HI, I am Lisa Goldsworthy with ACE Carpet and Upholstery Care in Denver, Colorado.
And in this segment, we are going to talk about what you should do when you have a spill on your carpet.
Take immediate action, got the spill, take immediate action.
First thing is to take a white towel, white cotton tile and blot.
Never scrub, never ever scrub.
Look what I got just from that blotting right there.
And just be patient and blot.
Put some muscle in to it.
Just continue your blotting.
Okay?
I am getting a lot of liquid out.
Continue to blot until the area is dry.
Now, you will find with any spill, especially one of that magnitude, that was quite a bit of liquid that went in there, it goes through the bottom.
In this particular case, I feel that it is wet, however, we don't see the color in here.
But it is wet.
So you just want to blot.
And already, already, this carpet sample pretty dry to the touch.
Again, the Scotchgard helped us but even a carpet without the Scotchgard, if your carpet is older, its okay.
Just this blotting technique really does a lot.
So that?s really the most important thing you can do in a spill; is take a white towel and blot it.
And be patient.
You want it dry as soon as possible.
So the other thing I would highly recommend is to take a fan and just put it on the area and let it dry.
Now look. Its kind of matted down a little bit from my blotting right? So, just take it, bring that carpet nap up.
Bring it back up.
And the reason why you want to do that is because then the air flow can get in through this carpet and that you decrease that drying time.
You want to get that carpet as dry as possible as quickly as possible.
So, good job.